<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Configuration on Rimon&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://rimonmostafiz.com/tags/configuration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Configuration on Rimon&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:19:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rimonmostafiz.com/tags/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Bean Wiring Using JavaConfig</title>
      <link>https://rimonmostafiz.com/blog/spring-bean-wiring-using-javaconfig/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 10:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rimonmostafiz.com/blog/spring-bean-wiring-using-javaconfig/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I wrote about how can we implicitly wire beans automatically in Spring container. In my previous post I created a new maven project and started writing code so that we can understand the topics more clearly. In this post, I am documenting my learning of how we can wire bean using Explicit Java Configuration. I will work on the same project I have created earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Application Context and Configuration Metadata</title>
      <link>https://rimonmostafiz.com/blog/spring-application-context-and-configuration-metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 06:42:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rimonmostafiz.com/blog/spring-application-context-and-configuration-metadata/</guid>
      <description>In the last post of Spring Diary, we discussed the basics of spring IoC Container and we saw a high-level view of how Spring Container works.
In this post, we will learn about how can we Instantiate a Spring IoC container(using ApplicaitonContext Interface) and configure that container using configuration metadata.
Spring IoC container consumes a form of configuration metadata. This configuration metadata represents how you as an application developer tell the Spring container to instantiate, configure, and assemble the objects in your application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spring IoC Container</title>
      <link>https://rimonmostafiz.com/blog/the-spring-ioc-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rimonmostafiz.com/blog/the-spring-ioc-container/</guid>
      <description>Overview There is some confusion these days over the meaning of inversion of control due to the rise of _IoC containers. _An IoC container is a common characteristic of frameworks that implement Inversion of Control (IoC).
Some people confuse the general principle here with the specific styles of inversion of control (such as dependency injection) that these containers use. It is a process whereby objects define their dependencies, that is, the other objects they work with, only through constructor arguments, arguments to a factory method, or properties that are set on the object instance after it is constructed or returned from a factory method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a bit of spring: part one</title>
      <link>https://rimonmostafiz.com/blog/a-bit-of-spring-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 09:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rimonmostafiz.com/blog/a-bit-of-spring-part-one/</guid>
      <description>Spring MVC Java Configuration Hi All, This _should_ be the first in a series of &amp;ldquo;Rimon learns Spring&amp;rdquo; type blog posts I plan on writing as I learn bits of Spring. I am just documenting my learnings, not advising others based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.
Spring traditionally supports two types of configurations:
 XML based configuration
 Annotation-based configuration
  This post is about a bare minimum annotation-based configuration of spring MVC.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>